Finding Aid for Walker Lee Cisler Papers 1899-1994
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Overseas Advisory Associates (OAAI), 1974-1993
  - Telexes, 1979-1989
    - U.S.S.R., 1980-1987
      - 1980-1985, 6 folders (Box 29)
      - Ministry of Power, 1986-1987 (Box 29)
    - Venezuela, 1981 (Box 29)
    - West Germany, 1980 (Box 29)
- Other Affiliations, 1918-1989
  The Other Affiliations series (2 linear ft.; 1918-1989) contains records of Walker Cisler's affiliation with the Economic Club of Detroit, New Detroit, the Freuhauf Corporation, and other civic and fraternal organizations.
  - Economic Club of Detroit, 1947-1978
    - Correspondence, 1959; 1965; 1973 (Box 30)
    - Introductions, 1947-1978
      - Programs at which WLC presided, 1969-1975 (Box 30)
      - Programs in which WLC participated, 1947-1978
        - 1947-March 1957 (Box 30)
        - September 1957-March 1959 (Box 30)
        - September 1959-October 1963 (Box 30)
        - February 1964-September 1965 (Box 30)
        - April 1965-December 1966 (Box 30)
        - January 1967-September 1968 (Box 30)
        - October 1968-December 1968 (Box 30)
        - January 1969-March 1969 (Box 30)
        - April 1969-September 1969 (Box 30)
        - November 1978 (Box 30)
  - New Detroit, 1967-1977
    - Articles of Incorporation and Resolutions, 1968 (Box 30)
    - Bylaws, 1969 (Box 30)
    - Correspondence, 1972-1975 (Box 30)
    - Recreation Committee, 1973-1975 (Box 30)
    - Special Issues Committee, 1972; 1977 (Box 30)
    - Housing Sub-Committee and Task Force, 1969-1975 (Box 30)
    - Statements, 1970-1971 (Box 31)
    - Newspaper Clippings and Press Releases, 1967-1973 (Box 31)
    - "Moving Detroit Forward Plan", Undated (Box 31)
    - "Proposal for Detroit's Revitalization", Undated (Box 31)
    - Reports, 1968-1973
      - "Progress Report of the New Detroit Committee", 1968 (Box 31)
      - "Detroit: The New City", 1971 (Box 31)
      - "Inside New Detroit: Progress Report", 1973 (Box 31)
  - Fruehauf, 1918-1989
    - Bylaws, 1980 (Box 31)
    - Correspondence, 1976-1979 (Box 31)
    - Annual Meeting of Shareholders, 1977-1980 (Box 31)
    - Annual Reports, 1976-1977; 1979 (Box 31)
    - Board of Directors, 1961-1980
      - Minutes, 1961-1980
        - 1961 (Box 31)
        - 1976-1977 (Box 31)
        - 1978-1980 (Box 31)
      - Executive Committee Minutes, 1978 (Box 31)
    - Excise Tax Case, 1975-1979 (Box 31)
    - Financial Records, 1918-1989
      - Financial Statements, 1977-1979
        - May 1977-September 1978 (Box 31)
        - December 1978-January 1979 (Box 31)
      - Flash Results, 1976-1980 (Box 31)
      - Internal Accounting Control Audit, 1979 (Box 31)
      - Moody's Investors Service and Standard & Poor's, 1979 (Box 31)
      - Operating Statistics, 1918-1989 (Box 31)
    - Press Releases, 1976-1979 (Box 31)
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1978 (Box 31)
  - Committee For Economic Development, 1968-1978 (Box 31)
  - Detroit Educational Television Foundation, 1957; 1968 (Box 31)
  - Detroit Tomorrow Committee, 1958-1959 (Box 31)
  - Detroit's 250th Birthday Festival, 1951-1952 (Box 31)
  - Knights Templar, 1975 (Box 31)
  - Northwestern Highway Citizens' Advisory Committee, 1975-1977 (Box 31)
  - Distinguished Visitors, 1951-1953
    - King and Queen of Greece, 1953 (Box 31)
    - Prime Minister Alcide de Gaspari (Italy), 1951-1952 (Box 31)
    - Queen Juliana (Netherlands), 1952 (Box 31)
- Visual Materials, 1899-1985
  Visual Materials (1.5 linear and 1 oversize volume; 1899-1985) includes photographs and photograph albums. The photographs include portraits, group photographs, and photographs arranged by topic. All group photographs include Walker Cisler. The albums consist of commemorative volumes prepared on the occasion of special events, such as WLC's retirement as chairman of the board of Detroit Edison.
  - Photographs, 1899-1985
    - Portraits, 1941-1969
      - Walker Cisler, 1941-1969; Undated (Box 32)
      - Gertrude Cisler, 1965; Undated (Box 32)
    - Group Photographs, 1899-1985
      - Alphond, Herv (French Ambassador), 1963 (Box 32)
      - Bernhard (Prince)-Netherlands, circa 1965 (Box 32)
      - Bradley, General Omar, 1954 (Box 32)
      - Carter, Jimmy, Undated (Box 32)
      - Castillo-Armas, Colonel Carlos (President of Guatemala), 1955 (Box 32)
      - Cisler, Gertrude, 1963; Undated (Box 32)
      - Cisler, W.L. (with sister Frances), 1899 (Box 32)
      - Dunn, Ed, 1963 (Box 32)
      - Fisher, Max, Undated (Box 32)
      - Ford, Gerald, Undated (Box 32)
      - General Motors Executives, Undated (Box 32)
      - Hori, Yoshimich (Sons of), who was killed in plane crash, 1971 (Box 32)
      - Huebner, Adele (Ambassador), 1962 (Box 32)
      - Humphrey, Hubert H., 1967 (Box 32)
      - Inouye, Goro, 1967 (Box 32)
      - Iran, Shah of, 1966; 1968 (Box 32)
      - John Paul II (Pope), 1985 (Box 32)
      - Johnson, Lyndon B., 1964 (Box 32)
      - Kennedy, Edward, 1969 (Box 32)
      - Kigar, Don, 1964 (Box 32)
      - McMullen, George, 1963 (Box 32)
      - Nixon, Richard, 1961 (Box 32)
      - Park, General (Korea), 1969 (Box 32)
      - Peter II (Yugoslavia King), 1959 (Box 32)
      - Romney, George, 1963 (Box 32)
      - President of Indonesia), 1956 (Box 32)
      - Thailand Prime Minister, 1968 (Box 32)
      - Miscellaneous, 1948-1972; Undated (Box 32)
    - Topical File, 1916-1978
      - Atomic Industrial Forum, 1953; 1963
        - Press Conference, 1953 (Box 32)
        - Anniversary, circa 1963 (Box 32)
      - Bike to Work, 1972; Undated (Box 32)
      - Club 58 Luncheon, 1955 (Box 32)
      - Collages, circa 1962 (Box 32)
      - Cornell, 1966; 1972
        - 50th Reunion, 1972 (Box 32)
        - Board of Trustees, 1966 (Box 32)
      - Detroit Convention Bureau's 75th Anniversary, 1971 (Box 32)
      - Detroit Edison, 1956-1972
        - Board Material, 1966; 1969
          - Annual Meeting, 1966 (Box 32)
          - Energy Committee at Fermi, 1969 (Box 32)
        - Connecting Channels Ground Breaking, 1957 (Box 32)
        - Dedication of Unit #9 name in honor of Harlan Hatcher, 1968 (Box 32)
        - Enrico Fermi Atomic Power Plant, Undated (Box 32)
        - Fermi Dedication, August 8, 1956 (Box 32)
        - Handyman Van Project, 1968 (Box 32)
        - Lighting Boiler at St. Clair, 1969 (Box 32)
        - Russian Transformer Movement, 1972 (Box 32)
        - Start-Up #3 River Rouge, 1958 (Box 32)
        - Synchroscope Luncheon, 1963 (Box 32)
        - W.L.C. with Fermi Model, Undated (Box 32)
        - G. Mennen Williams with Fermi Model, Undated (Box 32)
      - Detroit's 250th Birthday, 1951 (Box 32)
      - Economic Club of Detroit, 1971-1972
        - Astronauts, 1971 (Box 32)
        - European Trip, 1972 (Box 32)
      - Edison Electric Institute, 1964; 1966
        - 17th Annual Round Table Conference, 1964 (Box 32)
        - 34th Annual Convention, 1966 (Box 32)
      - G.E. Locomotive Assembly Plant, 1969 (Box 32)
      - Greater Detroit Board of Commerce Cruise, 1964 (Box 32)
      - Greece, circa 1973 (Box 32)
      - Hoover Medal, 1962 (Box 32)
      - Ice Storm, 1968 (Box 32)
      - Invest in America, 1964 (Box 32)
      - Japan Atomic Industrial Forum, 1956 (Box 32)
      - Lunch for George Romney, 1969 (Box 32)
      - Mackinac Bridge Dedication, 1958 (Box 32)
      - Michigan Economic Development Commission, 1952 (Box 32)
      - Nagasaki Bomb Site, 1976 (Box 32)
      - National Conference of Christians and Jews, Brotherhood Dinner, 1968 (Box 32)
      - Personal, 1916-1978
        - High School, 1916; 1972
          - Football Team, 1916 (Box 32)
          - 55th Reunion, 1972 (Box 32)
        - Pancake Brunch, 1964 (Box 32)
        - Ponies at Gradyville, circa 1973 (Box 32)
        - Rippes' 25th Wedding Anniversary, 1978 (Box 32)
      - Philippines, 1974 (Box 32)
      - Poe Lock Dedication, 1969 (Box 32)
      - Presentation of Steam Locomotive, 1958 (Box 32)
      - Russia, 1958-1961 (Box 32)
      - Thomas Alva Edison Foundation, 1958-1972
        - 10th Institute, 1959 (Box 32)
        - Edison Day at Stuttgart, 1972 (Box 32)
        - Edison Birthday, 1958; 1967; 2 folders (Box 32)
        - International Birthday Celebration in Japan, W.L.C. with Prince and Princess, circa 1969 (Box 32)
        - Science Youth Day, 1963 (Box 32)
      - Thu Duc Project (Saigon), 1972 (Box 32)
      - USO, 1963-1969
        - USO of Metro Detroit, 1963 (Box 32)
        - Distinguished Service Award, 1966 (Box 32)
        - National Council, 1969 (Box 32)
      - War Service, 1943-1944
        - 1944, Undated (Box 32)
        - Office of War Utilities, 1943 (Box 32)
        - Power Facilities, Undated (Box 32)
      - Western Society of Engineers, Washington Award, 1957 (Box 32)
      - White House Conference on Natural Beauty, 1965 (Box 32)
      - World Energy Conference, 1972; 1974
        - 1974 (Box 32)
        - U.S. National Committee, 1972 (Box 32)
  - Photograph albums
    - Commemorative volume prepared on occasion of WLC's retirement as chairman of the board of Detroit Edison, 1975 (Volume 1)
      (contain correspondence and photographs from different phases of WLC's Detroit Edison career)
    - Album: Twenty-first Hoover Medal Award Presentation to Dwight D. Eisenhower, 1961 (Box 33)
      (contains photos, program, address of S.L.A. Marshall, and related material)
    - Album: Visit of Premier Alcide de Gasperi to Detroit, Michigan, September 22-23, 1951 (Box 33)
    - Album commemorating the visit of Her Majesty the Queen of the Netherlands and His Royal Highness the Prince of the Netherlands to Detroit, Michigan, April 1952 (Box 33)
    - Album commemorating the visit of their majesties King Paul and Queen Frederika of the Hellenes to Detroit, Michigan, November 1953 (Box 33)
    - Album commemorating visit of Spanish government officials to Detroit (Box 33)
    - Album of photos and text from Detroit News article on "reactornauts", 1962 (Box 33)
      (re repair of the nuclear reactor at the Monroe power plant)
    - Album: WLC's visit to Doxiadis Associates and the Athens Center of Ekistics, September 2-5, 1965 (Box 33)
    - Album: Memories of a visit to the United States with members of the Organizing Committee for the 1974 World Energy Conference, 1972 (Box 33)
    - Album: Memories of a visit to the United States with members of the Organizing Committee for the 1974 World Energy Conference and members of the U.S. National Committee, 1973 (Box 33)
- Sound recordings
  Sound recordings (5 reels; 1958 and 1973) consists of a speech of WLC at the dedication of the Mackinac Bridge in 1958, and a series of four lectures given at Albion College in 1973 on the topic of energy.
  - Remarks of WLC at dedication of the Mackinac Bridge, 1958; reel-to-reel tape; 7 in. 7.5 ips (Box 33)
  - Albion College series on energy, 4 reels 7 in.
    - Energy in Human Affairs, October 16, 1973 (Box 33)
    - U.S. Energy Resources: Private/Public Management, October 25, 1973 (Box 33)
    - Earth: The International Spaceship, November 1, 1973 (Box 33)
    - Futures: Dark Glass and Crystal Ball, November 8, 1973 (Box 33)